RÉSUMÉ OF Nityananda Das

Present Address: 57/ V/6, Uttor Maniknagar, Dhaka-1203 Contact no.: **01912-71 38 35** E-mail: nitto das@yahoo.com



Objective

To build the career in any reputed organization in a mid level management position having the intention to work with honesty, sincerity and to learn, grow by integrating my knowledge and skills and to add value to the organization to be served and explore my potentials and eventually take greater responsibilities and to face the challenge of the time.

Professional Qualifications

• Chartered Accountancy Course Completed (CACC) under The Institute of Chartered Accountants of Bangladesh (ICAB)

Academic Qualifications

2008 : Master of Business Studies (MBS) in **Accounting**, 2nd Class, National University (Govt.

(Held in May 2011) Bangla College, Dhaka);

2007 : B.Com Honours in **Accounting**, 2nd Class, National University (Govt. M M College,

(Held in Jun 2009) Jashore);

2003 : H S C (Business Studies), GPA 3.80 / 5.00 (Without fourth Subject), Dr. Abdur Razzak

Municipal College, Jashore Board;

2001 : S S C (Science), GPA 3.88 / 5.00 (Without fourth Subject), Jashore Zilla School, Jashore

Board.

Job Experience

<u>Sr. Executive</u> (<u>Internal Audit,</u> <u>From 18.08.2013 –</u> to present)

Prime Group Of Industries

Company Location: Sena Kalyan Bhaban (8th Floor), 195 Motijheel C/A Department: Internal

Audit Division

Duties/Responsibilities:

- Review operations to ascertain control needs and to recommend, develop and maintain solutions to business and financial problems.
- To assists Head of Department efficiently and effectively by proper implementation of latest pre-audit and post audit system.
- To prepare Annual Audit Plan to cover all areas of the Company.
- Responsible for details of audit reports and analysis.
- Ensure internal control procedures and related compliances.
- Periodic and surprise Audit of Material Inventory of other departments and revenue transactions of the departments dealing with cash.
- Periodically visit to the sister concerns of the group regarding review the internal control environment.
- To prevent and identify all major risks such as financial fraud, pilferage etc.

- To conduct Market survey for rate and prepare report.
- Capable of handling multitasking activities and working under pressure.

Professional Experience

CACC (Chartered Accountancy Course Completed) from Nurul Faruk Hasan & Co.(nufhas) Chartered Accountants, Deloitte Bangladesh, for a period from 01 June 2010 to 17 August 2013 (03 years 02 months and 17 days).

Worked as an **articled student** in Nurul Faruk Hasan & Co. (nufhas); Chartered Accountants. During my CA Articleship Period some of the major clients working for Nurul Faruk Hasan & Co. (nufhas).

Telecommunication Industry:

Robi Axiata Bangladesh Limited.

Finance activities and preparatory work for BTRC regulatory audit (Duration Jan 2012 to Dec 2012)

- Analysis of Robi's statutory audit reports for the years from 1997 to 2010 (14 years) and preparation of various analyzed report for the purpose of Bangladesh Telecommunication Regulatory Commission's (BTRC) special audit;
- To check and confirm the compliance with the laws, regulation and various requirements of BTRC for various operational aspect of Robi Axiata BD Ltd;
- Preparation of monthly purchase register (Musok-16);
- Arrangement of local and foreign Remittance file;
- Arrangement of VAT and Tax Challan files;
- Arrangement of LC files;
- Database Creation and Management of bill of entry;
- Database Creation and Management of local and foreign loan;
- Calculation and deduction of Tax and VAT from vendors' invoice;
- Preparation of VAT and Tax treasury Challan to deposit into the government;
- Reconciliation among all the regulatory reports;
- Preparation of Special format database of accounting records and documents based on the suggestion given by the Robi's finance team;
- Preparation of monthly financial reports;
- Routine work.

Call centre Industry:

Inspire Communication Limited

Statutory Financial Audit

Garments Industries:

LSI Industries Ltd. (DEPZ)

- Fixed Assets verification
- Reconciliation between fixed assets register and physical verification

I.P Jaq Knitting Ltd. Zong Sine Textile Ind. Ltd. Dongmi Textile Co. Ltd.

Linmark Int.(BD) Limited

- Statutory Financial Audit
- Statutory Financial Audit
- Statutory Financial Audit
- Statutory Financial Audit

A-Tex Int. Ltd. Jo-Y-Jo Ltd.

- Statutory Financial Audit
- Accounting System design

Financial Institutions:

DBH (Delta Brac Housing)

- Fixed Assets verification
- Reconciliation between fixed assets register and physical verification

Oil, Gas and Power Generation Industries:

MJL (Mobil Jamuna Limited)

- Fixed Assets verification
- Reconciliation between fixed assets register and physical verification

Pendekar Energy

(A Malaysian power generation company-Bangladesh Operation)

The special review on 1,121 invoices submitted and settled for one vendor for a certain period to confirm the invoice payment and the actual closing balance of that particular vendor.

Academic Institution:

Shapporo Dental College, Dhaka

Statutory Financial Audit

Toilitries Industries:

Unilever Bangladesh Limited

Inventory Counting and reconciliation with SAP

Food and Beverage Industry:

Coca- Cola Far East Ltd.

Bangladesh Branch

- Book-keeping and Accounting functions
- Monthly financial reporting
- Payment processing
- Employees taxation matters
- Verification and reconciliation of concentrate stocks
- Physical verification and reconciliation of cooler(2013)
- Damaged Stock Audit (2013)

Non Government Organization(NGOs):

HELVETAS Swiss Intercooperation(HSI)

(Sharique and Samriddhi Project)

Statutory Financial Audit

Disabled Rehabilitation Research Association (DRRA), Kalama Shishu Niketan (KSN) Project

Statutory Financial Audit

Center for Natural Resource Studies(CNRS)

(Shiree Project)

Statutory Financial Audit

Village Education Resource Center (VERC, Protiva project)

Statutory Financial Audit

Training and Workshop

January 2012

Training on Security policy of Robi Axiata (BD) Limited.

Training on preparation of Income Tax return with

June 2011

sophisticated software Tax Tools. Nurul Faruk Hasan & Co.

(nufhas) Chartered Accountants.

January 2011 Training on Accounting software (Tally) installation, chart of

accounts preparation with accounting software.

Nurul Faruk Hasan & Co. (nufhas)

Chartered Accountants.

Extra-Curricular Activities:

 Secretary of Alumni Association of Jashore Zilla School, Jashore (2008-2009);

Producer & trainer of some handicrafts.

Languages Proficiency

English: Fair both in oral and written presentation;

Bengali: Standard in writing and speaking.

Computer Literacy

Spreadsheet application and word-processing:

MS Word, MS Excel, Power point

Operating system:

Windows 98, Windows XP, Windows 7

Efficient in the operation of E-mail, internet browsing.

Distinctive Qualities

Hard working and dynamic

• Rationally motivated and sincere

Excellent interpersonal skill and team player

Strong communication skill

Able to work under pressure

Results driven

• Excellent follow-up and responsiveness

• Like to take challenges

Personal Information

Father's Name : Late Haripada Das, MA

Mother's Name : Damyanti Das

Date and Place of Birth : 25 October 1986, Jashore, Bangladesh;

Permanent Address : House # 180, Bejpara Banani Road, Jashore ,P.O, P.S. &

District- Jashore

Religion : Hindu
Marital Status : Married
National ID # : 1005916083

References

Mr. Md. Nurul Haque, FCA;

Partner, Nurul Faruk Hasan & Co.; Chartered Accountants; Cell # 01713-414243; E-mail: nurul.nufhas@bcs-bd.com

• Mr. Md. Faruk Uddin Ahammed, FCA, CISA.

Partner Nurul Faruk Hasan & Co.; Chartered Accountants; Cell # 01713-038 738.

E-mail: faruk.nufhas@bcs-bd.com

